Human beings start putting each other into boxes
البشر يسارعوا لتصنيف بعضهم البعض في صناديق
the second that they see each other --
من اللحظة التي يرون فيها بعضهم البعض
Is that person dangerous? Are they attractive?
هل يشكل هذا الشخص خطرا؟ هل هم جذابين؟
Are they a potential mate? Are they a potential networking opportunity?
هل هم رفقاء محتملين؟ هل يشكلون فرصة محتملة للتواصل؟
We do this little interrogation when we meet people
نحن نقوم بهذا الاستجواب السريع عندما نلتقي بالناس
to make a mental resume for them.
لنشكل سيرة ذاتية في رؤوسنا عنهم
What's your name? Where are you from?
ما اسمك؟ من أين أنت؟
How old are you? What do you do?
ما عمرك؟ ماذا تعمل؟
Then we get more personal with it.
ثم نأخذ الأمر لمستوى أكثر خصوصية من هذا
Have you ever had any diseases?
هل كان لديك أي أمراض سابقة؟
Have you ever been divorced?
هل تطلقت من قبل؟
Does your breath smell bad while you're answering my interrogation right now?
هل نفسك سيء الرائحة وأنت تجيب على استجوابي الآن؟
What are you into? Who are you into?
ماذا تحب؟ من تحب؟
What gender do you like to sleep with?
ما هي ميولك الجنسية؟
I get it.
حسنا، فهمت.
We are neurologically hardwired
خلقنا بميول عقلية
to seek out people like ourselves.
للبحث عن أناس مثلنا
We start forming cliques as soon as we're old enough
نبدأ بتكوين مجموعات بمجرد أن نكون كبارا بما يكفي
to know what acceptance feels like.
لنعلم ماذا يعني قبول الآخرين.
We bond together based on anything that we can --
نحن نرتبط معا على اساس أي شي نستطيع عمله
music preference, race, gender, the block that we grew up on.
الاعمال الموسيقية، العرق، الجنس، الحي الذي تربينا فيه
We seek out environments that reinforce our personal choices.
نحن نبحث عن بيئات تعزز اختياراتنا الشخصسية
Sometimes, though, just the question "what do you do?"
أحيانا، مجرد سؤال "ماذا تعمل؟"
can feel like somebody's opening a tiny little box
يُشرعك كأن أحدا يفتح صندوقا صغيرا
and asking you to squeeze yourself inside of it.
ويطالبك أن تحشر نفسك بداخله
Because the categories, I've found, are too limiting.
لأني قد وجدت أن التصنيفات مُحددة جدا
The boxes are too narrow.
الصناديق ضيقة جدا
And this can get really dangerous.
وهذا يمكن أن يمثل خطرا حقيقيا.
So here's a disclaimer about me, though,
حسنا، سأبدأ بمقدمة عني
before we get too deep into this.
قبل أن ندخل في صلب الموضوع
I grew up in a very sheltered environment.
نشأت في بيئة محمية جدا
I was raised in downtown Manhattan in the early 1980s,
تربيت في قلب مدينة نيويورك، في مانهاتن في بداية الثمانينات
two blocks from the epicenter of punk music.
على مقربة من مركز موسيقى الـ"punk"
I was shielded from the pains of bigotry
تمت حمايتي من آلام التعصب الأعمى
and the social restrictions of a religiously-based upbringing.
والقيود الاجتماعية للتنشئة الدينية
Where I come from, if you weren't a drag queen or a radical thinker
من حيث نشأت، إن لم تكن رجلا يتصرف امرأة أو متحررا
or a performance artist of some kind,
أو فنانا من نوع ما
you were the weirdo.
كنت أنت الشاذ!
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It was an unorthodox upbringing,
لقد كانت تنشئة غير محافظة
but as a kid on the streets of New York,
لكن كأي طفل في شوارع نيويورك،
you learn how to trust your own instincts,
تعلمت أن أثق في غرائزي
you learn how to go with your own ideas.
تعلمت كيف أتماشى مع أفكاري الذاتية.
So when I was six, I decided that I wanted to be a boy.
لذا، عندما أصبحت في السادسة، قررا أني أريد أن أكون ولدا
I went to school one day and the kids wouldn't let me play basketball with them.
ذهبت للمدرسة ذات يوم، والأولاد لم يسمحوا لي بلعب كرة السلة معهم
They said they wouldn't let girls play.
قالوا أنهم لن يسمحوا للبنات باللعب.
So I went home, and I shaved my head,
لذا عدت للمنزل، وحلقت شعر رأسي
and I came back the next day and I said, "I'm a boy."
وجئت اليوم التالي وقلت: "أنا ولد"
I mean, who knows, right?
من كان ليكشفني، أليس كذلك؟
When you're six, maybe you can do that.
عندما تكون في السادسة، ربما يمكنك فعل أي شيء
I didn't want anyone to know that I was a girl, and they didn't.
لم أرد أن يكتشف أي أحد أنني بنت، وبالفعل لم يكتشفوني
I kept up the charade for eight years.
واصلت في المسرحية لثمان سنوات
So this is me when I was 11.
هذا أنا في سن الـ11
I was playing a kid named Walter
كنت أمثل دور فتى اسمه وولتر
in a movie called "Julian Po."
في فيلم اسمه "جوليان بو"
I was a little street tough that followed Christian Slater around and badgered him.
كنت فتى شوارع خشنا، تتبعت كريستيان سلاتر (ممثل) و أزعجته
See, I was also a child actor,
كنت حقا، ممثلا طفلا
which doubled up the layers of the performance of my identity,
وهذا ما حسّن جودة أداء تمثيل هويتي
because no one knew that I was actually a girl really playing a boy.
فلم يعرف أحد أني كنت بالحقيقة بنتا تؤدي دور ولد
In fact, no one in my life knew that I was a girl --
في الحقيقة، لم يعرف أحد في حياتي أني كنت بنتا
not my teachers at school, not my friends,
ولا حتى معلميني ولا أصدقائي
not the directors that I worked with.
ولا المخرجين الذين عملت معهم.
Kids would often come up to me in class
كثيرا ما كان الأطفال يأتونني في الفصل
and grab me by the throat to check for an Adam's apple
ويمسكون بحلقي ليفحصوا إن كان لدي تفاحة آدم
or grab my crotch to check what I was working with.
أو يمسكوا ما بين رجلي ليفحصوا ما كان عندي
When I would go to the bathroom, I would turn my shoes around in the stalls
عندما كنت أذهب للمرحاض، كنت أضع حذائي مقلوبا للداخل في الحجرة
so that it looked like I was peeing standing up.
حتى تبدوا كأني أتبول وأنا واقفة
At sleepovers I would have panic attacks
في المبيت عند أصدقائي كانت تصيبني نوبات فزع
trying to break it to girls that they didn't want to kiss me
محاولة إنهاء أي علاقة مع فتاة لم ترد تقبيلي
without outing myself.
من دون أن أكشف حقيقتي.
It's worth mentioning though
يجدر بالذكر
that I didn't hate my body or my genitalia.
أنني لم أكره جسدي أو أعضائي التناسلية
I didn't feel like I was in the wrong body.
لم أشعر أني في الجسد الخطأ
I felt like I was performing this elaborate act.
كنت أشعر أني أؤدي هذا الدور عن قصد.
I wouldn't have qualified as transgender.
أنا لا أؤهل نفسي كمتحول جنسيا
If my family, though, had been the kind of people to believe in therapy,
أسرتي كانت من النوع الذي يؤمن بالعلاج
they probably would have diagnosed me
كان من الراجح أن يُشخصونني
as something like gender dysmorphic
بنوع من التشوه في هويتي الجنسية
and put me on hormones to stave off puberty.
وكانوا ليداوونني بهرمونات لمنع بلوغي.
But in my particular case,
لكن في حالتي تحديدا
I just woke up one day when I was 14,
استيقظت يوما عندما كنت في الـ14
and I decided that I wanted to be a girl again.
وقررت أني أريد أن أكون بنتا من جديد.
Puberty had hit, and I had no idea what being a girl meant,
بلغت سن البلوغ، ولم تكن لدي أي فكرة ما كان يعني أن أكون بنتا
and I was ready to figure out who I actually was.
وكنت مستعدة لاستكشاف ما كنت حقا.
When a kid behaves like I did,
عندما يتصرف طفل مثلي،
they don't exactly have to come out, right?
لا يحتاجون لإعلان ميولهم الجنسية، أليس كذلك؟
No one is exactly shocked.
لم يكن أحد مصدوما حقا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But I wasn't asked to define myself by my parents.
لم يطلب مني والداي تعريف نفسي
When I was 15, and I called my father
عندما كنت في الـ15، اتصلت بأبي
to tell him that I had fallen in love,
لأخبره أني وقعت في الحب،
it was the last thing on either of our minds
لقد كان آخر شيء في أذهاننا،
to discuss what the consequences were
أن نناقش ما كانت العواقب،
of the fact that my first love was a girl.
لحقيقة أن حبي الأول كان لفتاة.
Three years later, when I fell in love with a man,
بعد ثلاث سنوات عندما وقعت في حب رجل،
neither of my parents batted an eyelash either.
لم يُصدم أو يسترغب أي من والداي بتاتا
See, it's one of the great blessings of my very unorthodox childhood
أحد أعظم النعم لتنشأتي غير المحافظة
that I wasn't ever asked to define myself
أني لم يُطلب مني إطلاقا تعريف نفسي
as any one thing at any point.
بتعريف أحادي في أي مرحلة من حياتي.
I was just allowed to be me, growing and changing in every moment.
سُمح لي بأن أكون أنا، بأن أكبر وأتغير في كل لحظة
So four, almost five years ago,
منذ حوالي أربع أو خمس سنوات
Proposition 8, the great marriage equality debate,
خرج مقترح رقم 8، وبدأ النقاش العظيم عن المساواة في الزواج،
was raising a lot of dust around this country.
ما أثار عاصفة من الغبار في هذا البلد.
And at the time, getting married wasn't really something
في ذلك الوقت، الزواج لم يكن يمثل شيئا لدي
I spent a lot of time thinking about.
لم يكن شيئا أمضيت كثيرا من الوقت في التفكير فيه
But I was struck by the fact that America,
لكني كنت مصدومة لحقيقة أن أمريكا،
a country with such a tarnished civil rights record,
الدولة التي تحمل سجلا مشوها في حقوق الحقوق المدنية،
could be repeating its mistakes so blatantly.
ممكن أن تعيد نفس الأخطاء بهذا الشكل الصارخ
And I remember watching the discussion on television
أتذكر مشاهدة النقاش على التلفاز،
and thinking how interesting it was
وأنا أفكر كم كان مثيرا للاهتمام
that the separation of church and state
أن الفصل بين الدولة والكنيسة،
was essentially drawing geographical boundaries throughout this country,
كان يرسم حدودا جغرافية على امتداد هذا البلد،
between places where people believed in it
بين أناس مؤمنين به
and places where people didn't.
وأناس غير مؤمنين به.
And then, that this discussion was drawing geographical boundaries around me.
وبعدها بدأ هذا النقاش برسم حدود جغرافية حولي
If this was a war with two disparate sides,
إن كانت هذه حربا بين جانبين يائسين،
I, by default, fell on team gay,
كنت أنا تلقائيا، مع فريق المِثليين
because I certainly wasn't 100 percent straight.
لأني لم أكن 100% غيرية الميول
At the time I was just beginning to emerge
في تلك الفترة كنت بدأت لتوي
from this eight-year personal identity crisis zigzag
في الخروج من أزمة هويتي التي استمرت 8 سنين
that saw me go from being a boy
والتي شهدت كوني ولدا
to being this awkward girl that looked like a boy in girl's clothes
لهذه البنت الغريبة التي بدأت كولد في ملابس بنت
to the opposite extreme of this super skimpy,
للنقيض المتطرف من كوني هذه الفتاة
over-compensating, boy-chasing girly-girl
الأنثوية التي تبحث عن الفتيان
to finally just a hesitant exploration of what I actually was,
إلى البحث المتمهل لماذا كنت حقا،
a tomboyish girl
فتاة مسترجلة
who liked both boys and girls depending on the person.
تحب كلا من الفتيان والفتيات بناء على الشخص.
I had spent a year photographing this new generation of girls, much like myself,
أمضيت سنة في تصوير جيل جديد من الفتيات اللاتي يشبهنني كثيرا
who fell kind of between-the-lines --
الذين يقعون ما بين الحدود
girls who skateboarded but did it in lacy underwear,
فتيات أحببن التزلج ولكن وهن يرتدين لباسا داخليا خطيا
girls who had boys' haircuts but wore girly nail polish,
فتيات بتسريحات شعر ذكورية، ولكن بطلاء أظافر بناتي
girls who had eyeshadow to match their scraped knees,
فتيات بتظليل حواجب يتناسب مع ركبهن المصابة
girls who liked girls and boys who all liked boys and girls
فتيات أحببن الفتيات والفتيان، وفتيان أحبوا الفتيات والفتيان
who all hated being boxed in to anything.
الذين جميعا كرهوا أن يوضعوا في أي صندوق
I loved these people, and I admired their freedom,
أحببت أولئك الناس، وأعجبت بحريتهم
but I watched as the world outside of our utopian bubble
لكني شاهدت العالم خارج فقاعتنا المثالية
exploded into these raging debates
ينفجر في هذه النقاشات الغاضبة
where pundits started likening our love to bestiality on national television.
حيث بدأ النقاد يشبهون الحب الذي لدينا إلى البهيمية على شاشات التلفزة.
And this powerful awareness rolled in over me
وهذا الوعي القوي استملكني
that I was a minority, and in my own home country,
بأنني كنت ضمن أقلية، ففي بلدتي
based on one facet of my character.
بناء على سمة واحدة في شخصيتي
I was legally and indisputably a second-class citizen.
كنت قانونيا وبلا شك مواطنا من الدرجة الثانية.
I was not an activist.
لم أكن ناشطة
I wave no flags in my own life.
أنا لا أرفع شعارات ولا أعلام في حياتي
But I was plagued by this question:
ولكن راودني هذا السؤال:
How could anyone vote to strip the rights
كيف يمكن لأي أحد أن يدلي بصوته لينتزع الحقوق
of the vast variety of people that I knew
عن شرائح واسعة من الناس الذين عرفت
based on one element of their character?
بسبب عنصر واحد في شخصياتهم؟
How could they say that we as a group
كيف يستطيعون أن يقولوا أننا كمجموعة
were not deserving of equal rights as somebody else?
لا نستحق حقوقا متساوية كأي أحد آخر؟
Were we even a group? What group?
أننا كلنا متطابقين في مجموعة؟ أي مجموعة؟
And had these people ever even consciously met a victim of their discrimination?
وهل سبق أن هؤلاء قابلوا أحد ضحايا عنصريتهم؟
Did they know who they were voting against and what the impact was?
هل كانوا يدركون ما كانوا يصوتون ضده وما أثار ذلك؟
And then it occurred to me,
وعندها خطر لي،
perhaps if they could look into the eyes
ربما إن تمكنوا من النظر في عيون هؤلاء
of the people that they were casting into second-class citizenship
الناس الذين كان يجعلون منهم مواطني درجة ثانية
it might make it harder for them to do.
لكان أصعب عليهم أن يفعلوا ما يفعلون.
It might give them pause.
ربما سبب لهم لحظة مراجعة
Obviously I couldn't get 20 million people to the same dinner party,
بالتأكيد لم أستطع أن أدعو 20 مليونا لنفس حفلة العشاء!
so I figured out a way where I could introduce them to each other photographically
لذا خرجت بطريقة لتعريف بعضهم لبعض من خلال التصوير
without any artifice, without any lighting,
من أي تصنع، من دون أي إضاءة
or without any manipulation of any kind on my part.
ومن دون أي تعديل من طرفي.
Because in a photograph you can examine a lion's whiskers
ففي الصورة تستطيع أن ترى شارب أسد
without the fear of him ripping your face off.
من دون الخوف من أن يلتهم وجهك
For me, photography is not just about exposing film,
بالنسبة لي، التصوير لم يكن عن عرض المشهد،
it's about exposing the viewer
بل كان عن تعريض المشاهد
to something new, a place they haven't gone before,
لشيء جديد، لمكان لم يذهب إليه من قبل
but most importantly, to people that they might be afraid of.
وبشكل أهم، تعريضه للناس الذين قد يكون خائفا منهم.
Life magazine introduced generations of people
مجلة "لايف" عرفت أجيال من الناس
to distant, far-off cultures they never knew existed through pictures.
لثقافات بعيدة لم يعرفوا بوجودها، عبر الصور
So I decided to make a series of very simple portraits,
لذا قررت أنا أقوم بسلسلة من الصور البسيطة
mugshots if you will.
كصور التوقيف البوليسي إن شئتم.
And I basically decided to photograph anyone in this country
ببساطة قررت أن أصور أي فرد في هذا البلد
that was not 100 percent straight,
لم يكن 100% (مستقيما) غيريا جنسيا
which, if you don't know, is a limitless number of people.
والذي كان -إن لم تكونوا تعرفوا- عددا لا متناهيا من الناس
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So this was a very large undertaking,
كان هذا حملا كبيرا جدا
and to do it we needed some help.
وللقيام بالمشروع احتجنا بعض المساعدة
So I ran out in the freezing cold,
خرجت في البرد القارس
and I photographed every single person that I knew that I could get to
وقمت بتصوير كل شخص أعرفه واستطعت الوصول إليه
in February of about two years ago.
في فبراير منذ حوالي السنتين
And I took those photographs, and I went to the HRC and I asked them for some help.
وأخذت هذه الصور وذهبت منظمة "حملة حقوق الإنسان HRC" وطلبت مساعدتهم
And they funded two weeks of shooting in New York.
مولت المنظمة أسبوعين من التصوير في نيويورك
And then we made this.
وبعدها أنتجنا هذا
(Music)
(موسيقى)
Video: I'm iO Tillett Wright, and I'm an artist born and raised in New York City.
فيديو: أنا "آي أوه تويلت رايت"، وأنا فنانة ولدت ونشأت في مدينة نيويورك
Self Evident Truths is a photographic record of LGBTQ America today.
"حقائق ذاتية التدليل" هو تسجيل تصويري لـLGBTQ في أمريكا اليوم
My aim is to take a simple portrait
هدفي هو أن آخذ صورة بسيطة
of anyone who's anything other than 100 percent straight
لأي أحد ليس 100% غيري جنسيا
or feels like they fall in the LGBTQ spectrum in any way.
أو يشعر أنه يقع في أي طيف الـLGBTQ بأي طريقة
My goal is to show the humanity that exists in every one of us
هدفي هو أن أظهر الإنسانية في كل فرد منا
through the simplicity of a face.
من خلال بساطة الوجه.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
"We hold these truths to be self-evident that all men are created equal."
"نؤمن أن حقيقة أن كل الناس يولدوا متساوين هي حقيقة ذاتية التدليل"
It's written in the Declaration of Independence.
هذا مكتوب في إعلان الاستقلال
We are failing as a nation
نحن نفشل كأمة
to uphold the morals upon which we were founded.
في أن نعيش للأخلاقيات التي وُجدنا على أساسها
There is no equality in the United States.
ليس هناك مساواة في الولايات المتحدة
["What does equality mean to you?"]
["ماذا تعني المساواة لك؟"]
["Marriage"] ["Freedom"] ["Civil rights"]
["زواج"]["حرية"]["حقوق مدنية"]
["Treat every person as you'd treat yourself"]
["عامل كل شخص كما تحب أن تعامل نفسك"]
It's when you don't have to think about it, simple as that.
ببساطة، عندما لا تكون مضطر للتفكير فيها.
The fight for equal rights is not just about gay marriage.
الكفاح لاجل المساواه ليس فقط عن الزواج المثلي.
Today in 29 states, more than half of this country,
اليوم في 29 ولاية, اكثر من نصف هذه الدولة
you can legally be fired just for your sexuality.
و وفقا للقانون، يمكن ان تطرد من عملك بسبب ميولك الجنسية.
["Who is responsible for equality?"]
من المسؤول عن المساواه؟
I've heard hundreds of people give the same answer:
سمعت مئات الناس يجيبون بنفس الاجابة:
"We are all responsible for equality."
" نحن مسؤولون عن المساواه"
So far we've shot 300 faces in New York City.
حتي الان لقد قمنا بتصوير 300 وجه في مدينة نيويورك.
And we wouldn't have been able to do any of it
و لم نستطع القيام باي شيئ منها
without the generous support of the Human Rights Campaign.
بدون الدعم من حملة حقوق الانسان
I want to take the project across the country.
أرغب في نشر المشروع في جميع انحاء الدولة.
I want to visit 25 American cities, and I want to shoot 4,000 or 5,000 people.
أريد زيارة 25 مدينة أمريكية و تصوير اربعة الاف او خمسة الاف شخص.
This is my contribution to the civil rights fight of my generation.
هذه هي مساهمتي لمعركة الحقوق المدنية بالنسبة لجيلي.
I challenge you to look into the faces of these people
اتحداك بأن تنظر في وجوه هؤلاء الناس
and tell them that they deserve less than any other human being.
و تخبرهم بانهم يستحقون اقل من اي انسان اخر.
(Music)
(موسيقي)
["Self evident truths"]
["حقائق واضحة وضوح الشمس"]
["4,000 faces across America"]
["اربعة الاف وجه من جميع انحاء امريكا "]
(Music)
(موسيقي)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
iO Tillett Wright: Absolutely nothing could have prepared us for what happened after that.
تيليت رايت: لا شيء على الإطلاق يمكن أن يحضرنا لما حدث بعد ذلك.
Almost 85,000 people watched that video,
حوالي 85000 شخص شاهد هذا الفيديو
and then they started emailing us from all over the country,
وبدأو مراسلتنا من جميع انحاء الدولة
asking us to come to their towns and help them to show their faces.
يطلبون منا مساعدتهم لاظهار وجوهم.
And a lot more people wanted to show their faces than I had anticipated.
و الكثير من الناس أرادو اظهار وجوهم
So I changed my immediate goal to 10,000 faces.
لذلك غيرت هدفنا الي عشرة الاف وجه.
That video was made in the spring of 2011,
صُنع ذلك الفيديو في ربيع 2011
and as of today I have traveled to almost 20 cities
و الي يومنا هذا لقد سافرت الي حوالي عشرين مدينة
and photographed almost 2,000 people.
و صورت حوالي الفين شخص.
I know that this is a talk,
اني اعلم ان هذه محادثة
but I'd like to have a minute of just quiet
و لكن دعونا نأخذ دقيقة صمت
and have you just look at these faces
و ننظر الي هذه الوجوه
because there is nothing that I can say that will add to them.
لأنه ليس هناك ما أستطيع أن أقول من شأنها أن يضيف اليهم
Because if a picture is worth a thousand words,
لانه، لو ان الصورة تساوي الف كلمة
then a picture of a face needs a whole new vocabulary.
فان الصورة لوجه تحتاج الي قاموس مفرادات جديد
So after traveling and talking to people
بعد السفر و التحدث الي الناس
in places like Oklahoma or small-town Texas,
في أماكن مثل مدينة أوكلاهوما او سمول تاون في تكساس
we found evidence that the initial premise was dead on.
وجدنا دليل علي ان النظرية الاولي قد انتهت
Visibility really is key.
الرؤية هي مفتاح للحل.
Familiarity really is the gateway drug to empathy.
التعود هي دواء وبوابة الى التعاطف
Once an issue pops up in your own backyard or amongst your own family,
بمجرد التطرق للموضوع في عائلتك
you're far more likely to explore sympathy for it
علي الارجح ، ستكتشف أنك على الأرجح ستتعاطف مع الأمر
or explore a new perspective on it.
او تكتشف وجهة نظر جديدة حول الموضوع.
Of course, in my travels I met people
بالطبع، في سفري قابلت اناسا
who legally divorced their children for being other than straight,
قانونيا الغوا ابوتهم لاطفالهم المثليين
but I also met people who were Southern Baptists
وايضا قابلت اشخاصا بروتستنت من الجنوب
who switched churches because their child was a lesbian.
غيروا كنيستهم لان ابنتهم مثلية.
Sparking empathy had become the backbone of Self Evident Truths.
اثارة التعاطف اصبحت العمود الفقري للحقيقة البديهية
But here's what I was starting to learn that was really interesting:
و لكن هذا ما بدأت تعلمه و كان حقا مثير للانتباه
Self Evident Truths doesn't erase the differences between us.
الاثبات الذاتي للحقائق لا تمحو الاختلافات بيننا
In fact, on the contrary, it highlights them.
في الواقع علي العكس تماما انها تظهرها.
It presents, not just the complexities
انها تمثل ليس فقط العقبات
found in a procession of different human beings,
وجدت في استيعاب شخص مختلف عنا
but the complexities found within each individual person.
و لكن ايضا تعقيدات وجدت داخل كل شخص منفردا
It wasn't that we had too many boxes, it was that we had too few.
المشكلة ليست اننا لدينا الكثيير من الصناديق، انما هي ان لدينا عدد صغير منها.
At some point I realized that my mission to photograph "gays" was inherently flawed,
في مرحلة ما أدركت أن مهمتي لتصوير "مثليون جنسيا" كانت خاطئة في جوهرها،
because there were a million different shades of gay.
لان هناك مليون نوع منهم.
Here I was trying to help,
هنا كنت احاول المساعد ة
and I had perpetuated the very thing I had spent my life trying to avoid --
ووقعت في الشيئ الوحيد الذي حاولت تفادية طوال عمري
yet another box.
صندوق اخر.
At some point I added a question to the release form
في مرحلة ما اضفت سؤال الي استمارة السماح بالنشر
that asked people to quantify themselves
انني سالت الناس لتقيّم نفسها
on a scale of one to 100 percent gay.
من واحد الي مئة في المئة مثلي
And I watched so many existential crises unfold in front of me.
وظهرت امامي العديد من المشاكل الموجودة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
People didn't know what to do
الناس لم يعرفوا ماذا يفعلون
because they had never been presented with the option before.
لانه لم يعرض عليهم هذا الخيار من قبل
Can you quantify your openness?
هل تسطيع تحديد مدى انفتاحك؟
Once they got over the shock, though,
و مع ذلك، بعد تجاوزهم الصدمة
by and large people opted for somewhere between 70 to 95 percent
اختار الناس إلى حد كبير عن ما بين 70 الي 95 في المئة
or the 3 to 20 percent marks.
أو علامات 3 في المئة إلى 20 في المئة.
Of course, there were lots of people who opted for a 100 percent one or the other,
بالطبع كان هناك الكثير من الناس الذين اختاروا 100 في المئة واحدة أو أخرى،
but I found that a much larger proportion of people
ولكنني وجدت أن نسبة أكبر بكثير من الناس
identified as something that was much more nuanced.
صنفوا كشئ اكثر تفاوتا
I found that most people fall on a spectrum of what I have come to refer to as "Grey."
وجدت ان معظم الناس يقعون في مجموعة يمكن وصفها "بالرمادي".
Let me be clear though -- and this is very important --
أسمحو لي ان اكون اكثر وضوحا-- وهذا هام جدا
in no way am I saying that preference doesn't exist.
لا يمكنني القول ان التفضيل ليس موجودا
And I am not even going to address the issue of choice versus biological imperative,
و انا لن أناقش مسألة الاختيار مقابل الحتمية البيولوجية
because if any of you happen to be of the belief
لانه لو كان اي منكم يعتقد
that sexual orientation is a choice,
أن الميول الجنسي هو اختيار،
I invite you to go out and try to be grey.
اناشدك بالخروج و المحاولة بأن تكون رمادي.
I'll take your picture just for trying.
سوف اخذ صورتك للمحاولة فقط .
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
What I am saying though is that human beings are not one-dimensional.
ما أقوله هو أن على الرغم من البشر ليسوا ذوي بُعد واحد.
The most important thing to take from the percentage system is this:
أهم شيء يمكن ان يؤخذ من النظام النسبي هو:
If you have gay people over here
انه لو لدينا المثليين هنا
and you have straight people over here,
و لدينا الناس المستقيمين هنا،
and while we recognize that most people identify
و عندما ندرك انه معظم البشر يصنفوا
as somewhere closer to one binary or another,
بقربهم من فصيل او اخر
there is this vast spectrum of people that exist in between.
هناك العديد من الناس موجودين في الوسط.
And the reality that this presents is a complicated one.
و الواقع انه الوجود في هذا الموضع اكثر تعقيدا.
Because, for example, if you pass a law
لأنه علي سبيل المثال، لو رأيت قانون
that allows a boss to fire an employee for homosexual behavior,
يسمح لرب عمل ما بطرد موظفه لأنه يتصرف كمثلي،
where exactly do you draw the line?
أين بالتحديد يمكن ان نرسم الخط؟
Is it over here, by the people who have had one or two heterosexual experiences so far?
هنا، بجانب الناس الذين خاضوا تجربة شذوذ او اثنان حتى الان؟
Or is it over here
أو انها تنتهي هنا
by the people who have only had one or two homosexual experiences thus far?
عند من لديهم تجربة أو اثنين فقط كمثيلي الجنس حتى الآن؟
Where exactly does one become a second-class citizen?
أين بالضبط يمكن للمرء ان يصبح مواطنا من الدرجة الثانية؟
Another interesting thing that I learned from my project and my travels
شيئ اخر مثير للاهتمام تعلمته من خلال مشروعي و اسفاري
is just what a poor binding agent sexual orientation is.
فقط، انه مدى ضعف الميول الجنسي كعامل للتقارب بين الناس.
After traveling so much and meeting so many people,
بعد السفر كثيرا و مقابلة العديد من الناس.
let me tell you, there are just as many jerks and sweethearts
اسمحوا لي ان اخبركم، انه هناك العديد من السخفاء و الطيبين
and Democrats and Republicans and jocks and queens
و الديموقرطيين و الجمهورين و الفرسان و الملكات
and every other polarization you can possibly think of
و كل نوع من التصنيفات يمكن ان تخطر على بالك
within the LGBT community
داخل مجتمع LGBT
as there are within the human race.
كالموجودة داخل الجنس البشري.
Aside from the fact that we play with one legal hand tied behind our backs,
وبصرف النظر عن حقيقة أننا نعمل بيد واحدة مقيدة بالقانون خلف ظهورنا،
and once you get past the shared narrative of prejudice and struggle,
و بمجرد عبور القصة المشتركة من الكفاح و الحكم المسبق،
just being other than straight
كوننا غير مستقيمين
doesn't necessarily mean that we have anything in common.
لا يعني بالضرورة اننا لدينا شيء مشترك.
So in the endless proliferation of faces that Self Evident Truths is always becoming,
لذلك في الانتشار اللامنتهي من الوجوه التي دائما ما تثبت الحقيقة البديهية ،
as it hopefully appears across more and more platforms,
والتي آمل ان تظهر عبر منصات اكثر واكثر
bus shelters, billboards, Facebook pages, screen savers,
محطات الحافلات، لوحات الاعلانات، صفحات الفيس بوك، شاشات الكمبيوتر
perhaps in watching this procession of humanity,
و يمكن من خلال مشاهدة هذا الموكب الانساني،
something interesting and useful will begin to happen.
شيء مثير للاهتمام و مفيد سوف يحدث.
Hopefully these categories, these binaries,
أملي هو أن هذه التصنيفات و الثنائيات،
these over-simplified boxes
هذه الصناديق المبسّطة
will begin to become useless and they'll begin to fall away.
ستصبح غير مجدية و تختفي بعيدا.
Because really, they describe nothing that we see
لأن في الواقع تصف شيء لا يمكن ان نراه
and no one that we know and nothing that we are.
و ليس شخص نعرفه او شيء نمثله.
What we see are human beings in all their multiplicity.
ما نراه هم بشر بكل أشكالهم.
And seeing them makes it harder to deny their humanity.
ورؤيتهم تجعل من الصعب علينا إنكار إنسانيتهم​​.
At the very least I hope it makes it harder to deny their human rights.
علي الاقل آمل ان يكون من الصعب ان تنكر حقوقهم الانسانية.
So is it me particularly
أذن فأنا تحديدا
that you would choose to deny the right to housing,
التي سوف تختار إنكار حقه في السكن،
the right to adopt children, the right to marriage,
حقه في تبني طفل و حقه في الزواج،
the freedom to shop here, live here, buy here?
حقه في حرية التسوّق هنا ، و العيش هنا، و الشراء هنا؟
Am I the one that you choose to disown
هل انا من اخترت لتتبرأ منه
as your child or your brother or your sister or your mother or your father,
كأبنك او اخوك او اختك او امك او ابوك،
your neighbor, your cousin, your uncle, the president,
جارك، قريبك، عمك، الرئيس،
your police woman or the fireman?
ضابطة الشرطة او رجل الاطفاء؟
It's too late.
لقد فات الاوان .
Because I already am all of those things.
لأنني بالفعل كل هذه الاشياء.
We already are all of those things, and we always have been.
نحن كلنا بالفعل كل هذه الاشياء و سوف نكون دائما.
So please don't greet us as strangers,
لذلك من فضلك ، لا تحيننا كغرباء
greet us as your fellow human beings, period.
حيينا كبشر مثلك تماما، نقطة.
Thank you.
شكرا
(Applause)
(تصفيق)